Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit.
I am Ba Finance and the founder of
Family First Financial Services.
Today I am presenting to you
an excellent product from Kotak Life Insurance called
Fortune Maximize. This plan
offers various options. There are also
many bonus options. This is a participating
bonus plan. So,
watch the full video to understand this plan. If you like the video,
please subscribe to my YouTube channel, Anil Rajbhar Triple FC.
Under this plan, you are given three options:
a Live
Future Maximizer and a Golden Air
Maxima.
You can select any of these three options.
You get a
bonus in this policy. This is a participating
policy. Three bonus options are also given.
You get it immediately. The
second option is cash bonus, but deferred. If you
wish, you can take that bonus after some time. You can put
it on waiting list for some time, you
can put it in the deferred period. The
third option is
full bonus. If you wish, you
can buy insurance against it. The insurance tax will be levied, that is,
you will pay it additionally.  You
can see this way, now let's talk about the
benefits in this policy,
here you get insurance for a long time,
you can get insurance till the age of 85 years,
till 85 years you can
also get the benefit of bonus, in this policy you
can take joint life plan, you
can also insure your spouse, that is,
both husband and wife will be insured in a single policy,
both will get benefit, you
can pay the premium as per your convenience,
you can pay annual premium, you
can pay monthly premium, quarterly premium,
you can select any premium payment mode as per your convenience, you will
get many riders, apart from six riders,
you can take term plus rider, you can
take accidental death rider, you
can take accidental death and disability rider, you can take term plus idea,
so according to your need you want to take
insurance or accidental, if
you feel that you have to do
more transportation, your travel has been
reduced, accident riders can be added,
critical illness can also be added if you  If you
want to add a bridal cover,
you can also add a rider for criticality. So, you can design your
plan according to your needs.
You will
also
get different options for premium payment in the policy. You can select free payment for as many years as you can afford, 6 years, 8 years, 10 years, 12 years, 15
years, as per your need.
In this, from a child of three months, if you
see the maturity maximum, then if you
select six years or 15 years for premium payment, then a person up to 50 years can
purchase this policy. If you
take premium payment for 8-10 or 12 years, then a person up to 55 years can
purchase this policy. You can take this
policy till 86 years.
Now let us understand the illustration of this product.
First of all, let us understand the
option like Goal Maximizer.
In that option, you are given three bonus options.
One is cash bonus which can be taken immediately. The
second is gas bonus which you
can defer.  You can do it for 5 years, 7
years and 10 years and the third option is
Pedicure Pediatrics, what you can do in this is
that you will get additional insurance
but your bonus will get accumulated in it
and if you need to withdraw it all at once then
you can withdraw it all at once. Let us
understand these three options, there
is a customer who is 35 years old, he is purchasing a
plan Kotak Fortune
Maximizer
and he invests in it for 15 years, the
policy term is 50 years because this
policy will run till 85, so he is saving 35 plus 50
lakhs, here he is selecting
instead of live immediately,
here you will see that for 35 years he is paying lakhs of rupees,
he has paid for 15 years, now we
see column number
minutes survival benefit,
mention it in yours, yes it is written in column number 11, you will
see this 41612 in survival benefit, it will keep
coming to you every year till you are 85,
this every year from the first year  From the first year
till 85 years, you have
3612000 written in it, so you have ₹100000
and a maturity of 36 lakhs is also coming,
now let's see
after 10 years, he will want to take the money,
column number 11 survival benefit, now see,
for 10 years he is not getting it, but from 11 years onwards, money of
84 thousand 53 rupees will start coming into his account every year
and on maturity, you will see in column number
16, he will also get a maturity of 63 lakh 96000,
so here if you like to take some money later for some time, you
can take it and see the final option, the
third option in Maximizer, Live
Goal Maximum, which is the third option in the front,
where you do not get immediate money,
you want to take the money all at once
or keep it deposited, the
good thing in this is that if you withdraw from this,
you will not see anything,
you are not getting any money here because this tree is like a
family member, caller  Look at number 10, it is getting
deposited, if you
want to withdraw Rs. 16,1584,000 deposited here, you
can do so, otherwise your death
benefit insurance tax will keep increasing in front of it
and you see, this time on maturity you will
not get Rs. 40 or 60 lakh, this time
they will get a big amount on maturity
and that amount will remain
because they were keeping the money deposited, so these
three options are reducing,
now let's see in the maximizer, the
second option which you had is
called Bright Future Maximum
for Marriage, if you have retirement then
you can utilize this feature
because in this you
need money immediately for 3 years on 16, 17, 18 every
year, then you can select this option or if you want money all at once then you can select this option, if you want money
continuously then you can
select it, you can do it as a
medicine, how do you
see,
suppose there is a customer, we have kept the same thing for 35 years, everything from this
here he has given the
option  I have selected Bright Future
Maximizer, there is a family option and
here you can take the lump sum money
and you have to do the vacuum allotment in five years. What will happen to
you? If
you type in caller number 11, then in the fifth
year you will get the money together, Rs. 2,33,000. You will
see here and if you
look at the maturity, you will also see a huge amount mutual, Rs.
1 crore 50 lakh. Now if we
look at the second option,
but this time he wants to take the money after 5 years
and after how many years, after 12 years, then let us
see here how it will be
[Music], you will get
maturity of Rs. 94 lakh in this,
so you can invest this money in your children's education,
which was for 5 years, if
you want to pursue higher education then you
can do it, in this way we reduce all the options.
Finally, the saving option like Golden
Years Maximizer will be done in the same
way, but this 60%
lump sum and money can be taken together and after that
you can do gas bonus or immediate  If you
want to do it, you can do it. For example, if there is a 40
year old person, he pays a
premium of Rs 2 lakh for 10 years and when
he turns 60, he will
get Rs 22 lakh on maturity. After that, if he has
selected addition on the policy, then he will get Rs 1 crore 4
lakh on maturity.
If he
wants to cash this payment, he can do so. In this way,
you will avail all these options. Other benefits and features of income tax benefits in the policy include
tax benefit in the Income Tax section.
You will get a grace period of 30 days in this policy
if you take an annual policy.
If you take it in monthly mode, then
you will have a grace period of 15 days. You will get a
revival period of 5 years in this policy.
If due to some reason you are not able to pay the premium, then
you can revive this policy by paying the late fee at one go for the number of
years' premium.
In this policy, you will get 15 days.  You will
also get a free look creation. If you purchase a policy
and you feel that
you have to cancel this policy for some reason, then
you can cancel it and
get your money back within 15 days. This option is
called free look creation. Surendra Benefit.
In this policy, you will also get Surendra Benefit. It
also gives immediate. If you want to take it in the first year, if you want to
take the bonus after waiting for a few years, then
deposit the bonus and then withdraw it all at once. You
can also do this in parts.
Keeping the education of your children in mind, after accumulating the
bonus, you can withdraw it for 3 years or 5 years at once. If you
want to take a policy from the point of view of your round coriander retirement, then you
can purchase it. Kotak Life
Insurance is a big brand of its own. You
can also purchase the policy according to the brand and the rates in the claim center of this
company are also very good. So, if you want to
buy this policy from me, then you
can call on my mobile number 9909403412. And if
you just want to get information by calling, then you  You
can also get information on phone by paying a small consultancy fee. If you
liked my video, then before leaving, do
subscribe to my channel. Thank you so much.